<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Ames Brigham</title>
    <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Ames Brigham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://michael-ames.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delivering palliative care in rural regions</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/palliative-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/palliative-care/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, state funding was changing for palliative care in New York, and would now favor fewer, larger grants shared between providers in a given region. Providers in two rural counties requested assistance from our graduate program to propose design solutions addressing long-standing challenges suitable for this new, more collective funding model.
To identify the primary challenges facing local agencies, our team of two students toured facilities, interviewed employees across multiple roles, reviewed the published academic literature, and identified new models and programs that had been successfully implemented in similar contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRIME Sleep</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/prime/</guid>
      <description>Up to 80% of individuals at end-of-life experience sleep disruption, severely affecting their quality of life and and that of their caregivers. The traditional treatment approach is pharmacological, and although medications can improve sleep, they frequently result in serious side effects such as delirium or an increased risk in falls. Treatments such as behavioral and environmental interventions have been shown to be safer and equally effective, but much of this research has yet to make its way into daily practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover MDI</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/mdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/mdi/</guid>
      <description>The Human Early Learning Partnership (HELP) at the University of British Columbia collects and disseminates population-level data on the well-being of children through the Middle Years Development Instrument (MDI). To increase uptake and support end-users’ understanding of these datasets, I worked with HELP to build its first online learning platform, Discover MDI.
 Discover MDI homepage  After reviewing insights collected through focus groups and interviews, I designed and launched a pilot website aimed at HELP’s target audiences: educators, healthcare workers, and local and regional government employees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncover Your Creeks</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/uncover-your-creeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/uncover-your-creeks/</guid>
      <description>The national urban environmental non-profit organization Evergreen launched a three-year project to build an urban watershed network, connecting municipal and regional governments, researchers, allied non-profit organizations, and volunteer citizen scientists.
With waterways so central to the ecology of the urban pacific northwest, the region needed better water quality data-sharing, more volunteer-supported data collection, and increased lay participation in local watershed planning.
The three-year project:
 Established volunteer citizen scientist teams in seven area watersheds Convened a working group of researchers to collaborate on a regional data-sharing platform Partnered with city staff to increase turnout at municipal watershed planning consultation sessions Hosted an annual Urban Watershed Forum Trained corporate employees in water quality monitoring as part of an organizational sustainability program Supported the work of other non-profits through joint fundraising   A sample of the year-end project report, describing the events of the Urban Watershed Forum  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorate</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/commemorate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/commemorate/</guid>
      <description>StoryCorps needed to turn a longstanding program recording the stories of participants with memory loss into a DIY model suitable for use by staff at long-term care facilities. As the lead consultant, I presented an initial program model to healthcare professionals and solicited feedback on its design.
I identified several challenges faced by end-users:
 lackof suitable recording spaces unfamiliarity with audio equipment difficulty explaining the project to patients and their families getting buy-in from colleagues and facility managementa connecting the project with other patient activities and company marketing  and focused the training content on addressing these common problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly adding calendar events with help from a little applescript</title>
      <link>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/applescripting-a-calendar-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-ames.github.io/work/applescripting-a-calendar-helper/</guid>
      <description>There are many kinds of information I enjoy tracking and reviewing in a digital format. Time is not one of them.
After almost two decades of using them in earnest, I’ve never quite clicked with digital calendars. When circumstances permit, I’ll always enjoy paper ones (especially comically large desk pads and wall calendars). But I can’t ignore the two main benefits of digital versions — reminders and scheduling with others. So I’ve been stuck with ical, google, and outlook calendars over the years and cursed every time I needed to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
